Inventory of the Taylor Family Papers 1903-1935
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections Research Center, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Taylor Family Papers 1906-1935
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary.
2006.35
Letters and papers from the Taylor family from 1906-1957.
Taylor Family
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to all researchers.
Scope and Content
Form of material and dates: Papers, 1907-1957, of the Taylor family including letters to and from the Taylor brothers having to do with family life and the Theta Delta Xi fraternity; papers, including receipts, a wedding invitation, Theta Delta Xi Newsletter, and newspaper clippings.
Contents List
- 1907-1957. (Box 1, Folder 1-5)
  Letters written and received by the Taylor Family
  chronological
  - 1907-1914. 19 Sept. 1907., 2PP. ALS (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Jackson Davis to Charles A. Taylor Jr. Letter discussing Jackson Davis coming down to Williamsburg and helping set up the Theta Delta Xi House on the College of William and Mary campus, and good luck wishes for finding new brothers. Also to tell Maddox that he will becoming coming down.
  - 1907-1914. 24 Sept. 1907., 3pp. ALS (Box 1, Folder 1)
    W. Hodges to Charles A. Taylor Jr. Letter to keep him [Hodges] up to date on the new men the Chapter is thinking to induct, and who from the Chapter will play for the football team this year [1907]. Also writing to ask about the Finances and to remind [Charles] talk to the treasurer.
  - 1907-1914. 27 April 1908., 1p. ALS (Box 1, Folder 1)
    W. Hodges to Charles A. Taylor Jr. Letter to arrange a brother meeting on Tuesday [28 April].
  - 1907-1914. 17 Dec. 1912., 1p. ANS (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Charles A. Taylor to Preston P. Taylor. Letter telling Preston to come up on Friday night or afternoon, and that he [Charles] will be waiting at the train station. There will be a luncheon that Friday at Business Men's Club and to let him [Charles] know if he [Preston] cannot come.
  - 1907-1914. 20 May 1914., 1p. TL (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Charlie [Charles A. Taylor Jr.] to Preston P. Taylor. He cannot make it down to see him, but is sending Irvin Craig to look at the college, asking Preston to show him around. Also that Mama, sister, Claudia [?] and Dorothy [?] are going to West Point. He also reminds Preston to mail Papa for any monthly expenses.
  - 1919-1923. 8 Jan. 1919., 1p. TLS. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    DuPont de Nemours and Company: Personal Division Allan Henry, Wilmington, Delaware to Charles A. Taylor Jr. Letter regarding reemployment, that the company is unable to take him back at this time. His name is still under consideration.
  - 1919-1923. Oct. 1921., 1p. TL (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Graner and Company, Inc. to J.C. Taylor. Letter answering the question: What shall I pay for my fall suit?
  - 1919-1923. 15 Nov. 1921., 1p. ALS (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Brother to J. Christian Taylor. Letter to send $15.00 and that he is expecting [J.C] for Thanksgiving.
  - 1919-1923. 23 April 1923., 1p. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    [Chas A?] to J. Christian Taylor. Letter telling [J.C.] to drop a line and asking him if he needs spring clothes; asking whether or not there is a Saturday baseball game and says he [Chas A?] might come down to see it.
  - 1919-1923. July 1923., 1p. ANS. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    M.J. White to Brother Taylor, Charles. Letter Giving the address of H.F. Juep[i]tt: 120W Adams St. Chicago, Ill. [H.F. Juep(i)tt] will send him the cost accounting and samples for the convention. [M.J. White] end letter stating feel free to call.
  - 1923-1924. 12 Dec. 1923, 1p. TLS. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    New York Life Insurance Company: Special Agent to H. Christian Taylor. Letter to the received amount of #32.22 on policy, Silias E. Taylor, and extends time for payment balance for 30 days.
  - 1923-1924. 26 Feb. 1924., 1p. TLS (Box 1, Folder 3)
    King Parish Co. to Mr. James Christian Taylor. Notice of $60.00 due on an accounting dating back to April [1923] and wants to collect these fund for movement of the company and the company awaits the check.
  - 1923-1924. 27 April 1924., 1p. ALS (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Charles A. Taylor to J. Christian Taylor. Letter to extend apology about not being able to make it down to see him, and asks how he is doing? [Charles] informs him that he has been sick all week while in Detroit and Chicago and that he met a Theta Delta Chi on the train. Includes two pieces of literature about The Capitol Limited, the train.
  - 1923-1924. 1 June 1924., 1p. TL. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Charles [Charlie] to James Christian Taylor. Letter stating that he does not need to worry about the money he put out from Edgar and that he returned home yesterday. States regret about making so little on the Ford Motor Co. assembly saying he should not continue, and that he should decide something soon. Also [Charlie] states he will try to find something better by hopefull the end of September.
  - 1923-1924 July 1924., 2pp. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Pap to Messer, Harper and Taylor. Letter asking a favor to get items supposedly mailed to him by Jimmy [?]. P.S. Jack [Chakay?] pro basketball with Portsmouth stating that they all know what that means.
  - 1924-1925. July 1924., 1p. ANS. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Edgar Taylor to Christian Taylor. Letter asking why not come down Friday morning to [PP?]. He also gives a description of his day as well as a message about not hearing from him lately.
  - 1924-1925. 20 August 1924., 1p. ANS. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    [Sisla?] to J.C. Taylor. Letter that father was glad to get the letter you sent. [Sisla?] has been home three weeks minus a few days. Papa wanted someone to stay home, and he is doing fine.
  - 1924-1925. Sept. 1924., 1p. ANS (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Edgar Taylor to J.C. Taylor. Dropping a card telling that the card to Lillian [?] was a tale of woe and that he will be leaving for William and Mary next Week and to write him in Williamsburg.
  - 1924-1925. [n.d.] 1924., 1p. TL. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Pap to Messer, Harper and Taylor. Letter letting them know that he received his clothes. Commentary about how the girls are hot and that he went to see Henry's plants, and that he will probably next be traveling over the Rockies for his next trip. Also about Paul and his idea of going back to pro-football.
  - 1924-1925. 23 Nov. 1925., 1p. ANS. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    [SE?] to Mr. Edgar Taylor. Note that he will be leaving Wednesday for Richmond and will stop by the house in Williamsburg to see if you want to come and if possibly two others might want to come.
  - 1935-1957; (n.d.) 6 March 1935., 1p TC. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Union Circulation Co to Chas A. Taylor. Letter investigating the order and will make a report in the near future.
  - 1935-1957; [n.d] Dec. 1935., 1p. TC. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Theta Delta Xi to Charles A Taylor. Note trying to locate the whereabouts of Alexander W. Martin.
  - 1925-1957; [n.d] Dec. 1935., 1p. TC. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Theta Delta Xi to Silas E. Taylor Note trying to locate the whereabouts of Alexander W. Martin.
  - 1935-1957; (n.d.) Dec. 1957., 1p. TCS. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    [Wec?] to [L.F. Maqruder?] Love Letter.
  - 1935-1957; [n.d] [n.d.], 2pp. AL. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    [Unknown] to J. Christian Taylor. Letter stating will send things you asked for. Incomplete letter with government notes on reverside of second page.
- 6-7 1906-1935., Misc. (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
  Invitations, Subcription notices, Documents.
  - 1906-1924. 17 May 1906., 1p. C. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Wedding Invitation to the wedding of Mr. and Mrs. George Putham Watkins to Miss [C?]laudiue Perkins.
  - 1906-1924. 31 March 1922., 1p. D. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Mr. J.C. Taylors J.B. Padgett statement for Cleaning, Pressing and Repairing.
  - 1906-1924. 17 Aug. 1923., 1p. D. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    J.C. Taylor subscription form to The Southside Sentinel, Dr.
  - 1906-1924. Nov. 1923., 1p. D. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Taylor, S.E. College of William and Mary Report Card.
  - 1906-1924. May 1924., 1p. PV. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    The Epsilon Hokum, to J.C. Talyor. Theta Delta Xi newsletter Vol. III No. 1.
  - 1935-[n.d] July 1935., 1p. PM. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Theta Delta Xi Press receipt to Charles A. Taylor Jr. Hand written on document is a note stating the news of the sudden death of Rev. William H. P[i?] ttus.
  - 1935-[n.d.] 24 Oct. [n.y.], 1p. NwsCl. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Newspaper clipping Headline, Tells How Klan Regards Negroes, Imperial Wizard also Defines Attitude of Order on Jews and Catholics.
- 19{03] - 1924 (Folder 8)
  - 19[03] - 1924 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1 Dec. 19[03]., NS. (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Note to C.A. Taylor from W.A. Bell and Bro. Received check for ($5.75) and thanks.
    - 16 July 1907., 4pp. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Letter to [Chas] Taylor from [J? Lowry] Sinclair regarding the summer and that he won't be in Middlesex but in China in August and reference to Theta Delta Xi.
    - Dec. 1912., NS. (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Note to Preston Taylor from WM[D.Lin?] letting him know the he will probably be down sometime during Christmas.
    - 12 May 1915., D. (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Check for Kirk Parrish for $5.50 written by J.C. Taylor.
    - 31 Jan. 1918., 4pp. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Letter to "Father" [Preston Taylor] from [Ruth] conveying details of everyday life and her going down to dancing school.
    - 17 Sep. 1921., 1p. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Letter to J. Christian Taylor from Charles Taylor. About sending a check for $10.00 and asking for a copy of his expenditures to find the $85.00 mentioned in the letter.
    - Feb. 1922., NS. (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Note to J. Christian Taylor from Edgar (?) about coming up for "Founders" Day.
    - 11 August 1924., NS. (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Letter to (J) Christian Taylor from Preston (Taylor) saying his was in Richmond to see their father, and letting him know that "Papa" was better after his operation and that he should be out in two weeks.
    - 8 April 1924., 2pp. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Letter to J. Christian Taylor from Charlie Taylor informing him of travel plans to Atlanta and Charlottesville and of volleyball games.
    - May 1924., NS. (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Note from Edgar (?) to J.C. Taylor letting him know that he didn't make the trip.
    - July 1924., N. (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Note to J.C. Taylor a "Dance to the Music of Waring's Pennsylvanians" on July 18th 1924.
    - Sep. 1924., NS. (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Note to J.C. Taylor from Edgar (?) asking why he has yet to answer his last letter. Mentions the hard work on the farm and that the tomatoes are coming fast. Plenty of hard work.
    - [n.d.] 1926., 6pp. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Letter to S.E. Taylor from Virginia [?] a love letter.
    - July 19[??]., N. (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Note to Preston Taylor from Unknown letting him know what time to come down on the A.C.L. and instructions when in Richmond.
    - [n.d.], 2pp. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Letter to J. Christian Taylor from [Charles Taylor] about the family and Charles' recent activities and travels.
    - [n.d.], 2pp. TLS. (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Letter to J. Christian from [Hattie ?] to express regret for Christian not being there the previous week while his brother Preston was in town. Also she asks how was the candy she sent and talks a little about a friend in Lynchburg.
    - [n.d.], 8pp. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Letter to Lt. Preston P. Taylor from Hattie retelling events at home, congratulations on his promotion and briefly about how 'lucky' he is and fortunate.